Guide to the Chai Feldblum papers
Feldblum, Chai papers
- Series III. Research Files
  - Dean c. DC (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Bottoms v. Bottoms (VA) (Box 11, Folder 42-43)
  - M.D. v. C.J. (DC) adoption (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Paramilitary (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Parenting (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Powell @ Harvard (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Colin Powell/Jt. Chief (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Press contacts (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Primetime Live transcript (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Privacy (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - People for the American Way (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Politics (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Privacy (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
  - Proposals from the Field (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Race analogies (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Race (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Research memos (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Research (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Research (Richard, Donna) (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Retroactivity (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - ROTC (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Security clearnce/risk (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Service connection (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Security issues (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Resumes (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Sexual harrassment of women (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - SIECUS fact sheet (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Studds (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Surveys & Articles (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - 1992 Survey of Social Issues in the Army (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Swann (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Speech: Public v. Private (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Testimony statements- legal (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Testimony (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - UCC (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Unit cohesion (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Veterans for Human Rights (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Volunteer- media and others (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Donald Dean Winn (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Witness intake forms (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Women in the military (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Benefits (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Amendments (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Letters re: C-SPAN (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Charts (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Floor statements, etc. (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Codification (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Gay/lesbian/bi veterans (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Senate transcripts: 3/29 to 3/31 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Member rankings (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Exclusion by Wells-Petry (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - "Military Justice Reporter" articles (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Articles- UCMJ (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - UCMJ policy modification drafts (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Magazine articles (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - UCMJ- articles (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Code, UCMJ, & Regs (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - UCMJ- Statute (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - UCMJ- Annotated statute (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - USMJ: Annotated statute sections (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - UCMJ (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Message: Legal panel (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - UCMJ: cases (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - CMS materials (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Floor statements (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Presidential press release (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Additional views of Kennedy (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Rand folder (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
  - First Amendment (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Selland (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 1/29/93 DOD statement and press conference by President (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Codification (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Meinhold/Hatter (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Post DOD policy Senate/House Hearings (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Notes (Box 13, Folder 16-18)
  - CMS info/news packet (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - CMS folder (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - "To Support & Defend: The Role of Homosexuals in the Military" video info. packet (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - "Tour of Duty" press kit (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - CMS Senate Hearings press kit (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Cases (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 25-26)
  - Miscellaneous CMS documents (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous memos/correspondence (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous (CMS?) (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - News articles (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - CMS booklet (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - News articles (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
  - Cases/law- gays- military (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - News articles (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - News clippings (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Magazine articles (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Info. re: Law and Order "Manhood" episode (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - CMS photos from the "Tour of Duty", Atlanta, New Orleans (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - News articles (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - News clippings (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "An Open Letter to the President..." Anti-ban lifting ad in The Washington Times (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - News clippings (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Statistics Related to DOD's Policy on Homosexuality, Expression (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - States - laws - research (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Articles and testimonies (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous articles/documents (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Howard (Hate Crimes Act) (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Gays in the military memos (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Article - Senate hearings - Gays in the military (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Buttino v. FBI - Don't ask, don't tell (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Regulations (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - "Don't Ask, Don't Tell" statute (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Gays in military: Misc. correspondence (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Eskridge: Desegregation analogy and moral arguments against ending the ban (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - DOD statement: Homosexuals in the military (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Floor statement: Gays in the military (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Schwartzkopf statement and rebuttal (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Falsehoods re: International comparison of gays in the military (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Congressional record: Intelligence Authorization Act (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Human Rights Campaign Fund (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Status vs. conduct (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - State privacy laws re: Sodomy (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Uniform Code of Military Justice (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Georgetown (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - DOD directive and law (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Discharge form (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Ban 11996 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Romer v. Evans (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Romer brief: Memos (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Evans v. Romer (trial transcript) (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Testimony on ENDA Senate labor 1 hr (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Legal memos (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Reports, 1980-1996 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence/memos, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Legislation/litigation, 1994-1997 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Articles/papers, 1993-1997 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Articles/papers, 1984-1997 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Articles/papers, 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Sexual Orientation and US Military Personnel Policy: Options and Assessment, 1993; Nation Defense Research Institute; Rand (Box 20)
  - New Ways Ministry's Symposium IV cassettes, 1997-03-07-1997-03-09; tr-11573-11584 (Box 20)
  - New Ways Ministry's Symposium IV cassettes, 1997-03-07-1997-03-09; tr-11585-11590 (Box 20)
- Series IV. CMS Organizational Materials
  - Original Incorporation Documents, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Employer # letter, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - CMSEF closing & 990 work papers, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Quarterly Tax Worksheets/Financial Reports, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Misc. financial information (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Monetary contributor correspondence [ RESTRICTED], 1994
- Series V. Videos
  - CMS Network Coverage, 1993-03-29; V-597 (Box 16)
  - MacNeil-Lehrer: Gays in the Military, 1993-03-29; V-598 (Box 16)
  - 13th Annual Film and Video Festival: "Communicating and Community: Multiple Visions, Multiple Strategies", 1993; V-599 (Box 16)
  - WCCO-TV Channel 4 (CBS), 1993-03-14; V-600 (Box 16)
  - Good Morning America/ABC News Interview with Eugene Giannunzio, 1993-04-02; V-601 (Box 16)
  - HRCF "Your Story, Our Story", V-602 (Box 16)
  - Part of the USA, V-603 (Box 16)
  - FOX news, ABC news, ACLU Press conference, Lift the Ban Rally, Schindler march, Lincoln Memorial, Vietnam Wall, Bob Hattoy speech, V-604 (Box 16)
  - Power Through the Media- Lift the Ban TV Commercials, 3 spots, 1993-04-02; V-605 (Box 16)
  - Zimmerman & Markman 1993 Presentation Reel, 1993; V-606 (Box 16)
  - Donahue "Press Copy" Gays in the Military, 1993-01-29; V-607 (Box 16)
  - "Ed Anderson's Journal" #6- Lesbians and Gay Men in the United States Military, V-608 (Box 16)
  - Law & Order, episode: "Manhood", 1993-04-15; V-609 (Box 16)
  - Parade Pictures Ad Hoc Video for the Campaign for Military Service- Demo Reel, 1993-02-15; V-610 (Box 16)
  - Doak Shrum Harris Carrier Devine CMS- "Wall" 102, :30, 1993-05-25; V-611 (Box 16)
  - Doak Shrum Harris Carrier Devine CMS- "West" 103, :60, 1993-05-04; V-612 (Box 16)
  - Doak Shrum Harris Carrier Devine CMS- Closed Captioned, "West" 103R :60, 1993-07-02; V-613 (Box 16)
  - "Uninvited Witnesses"- The Campaign for Military Service [broadcast standard format], Undated; V-614 (Box 16)
  - Doak Shrum Harris Carrier Devine- CMS- "Wall" 102, :30 [broadcast standard format], 1993-05-26; V-615 (Box 16)
  - Parade Pictures- "To Support & Defend", Partial Cut- In Progress, 1993-04-17; V-616 (Box 16)
- Series VI. Employment Non-Discrimination Act (ENDA)
  - Confidentiality (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - BNA chapter - S + G (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - FBI letter (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Frank bill (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Section 5538 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Boy Scout case (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Phillips v. Wisconsin Personnel Commission (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Gay civil rights drafts (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - S.H.R.M. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Executive order - access to classified information (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Helms amendments (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Gay Roundtable (status/conduct memo) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Status and conduct in queer equal protection litigation (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Dornan - 104th federal funds (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Romer v. Evans brief - misc. memos (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Romer v. Evans brief - anti-gay research (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Disparate Impact language (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Bills and cong. rec. 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Bills and cong. rec. 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Litigation, 1972-1993 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Articles and essays, 1986-1992 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - ENDA - 104th Congress - drafts, notes, 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Clinton's announcement, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Notes - Senate/House hearings (after DOD policy announced), 1993 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Testimony on ENDA Senate labor 1 hr, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - La Rock. Jean-Daniel -2D, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Gay Civil Rights bill/memos, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - EEOA section-by-section summary, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Q + A - for press conference (one-pagers) (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Talking points - politically sensitive Qs (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Indian tribes, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - ENDA support - private employers, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Meeting notes, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Sample letter of support, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - EEOA fax sheets, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Lambda "sexual orientation definition" memo, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - ENDA/PFLAG materials (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - (hrcf) ENDA v. California labor code, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Log Cabin Republicans - EEOA material, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Disparate impact, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Summaries of state provisions (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - LCCR Participant Info, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - EEOA Summary, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Court cases, 1971-1992 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Disparate impact/disparate treatment, 1991-1993 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Labor code 1102.1 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Section 245 research (1 of 2), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Section 245 research (2 of 2), 1994 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - ENDA: Corresp. Memos, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Steffan, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Cammermeyer v. Aspin, 1994-06-01 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - Religious exemption issue, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Rabbi Mayer Rabinowitz, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Status v. Conduct - Gays in the military (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - ENDA: Bill (103rd Cong.), 1995 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - ENDA: Preferential TMT, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - ENDA Section 4, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ENDA lang. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - ENDA - Wash. Blade article, 1995-06 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Additional articles, 1976-1998 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - ENDA history/footnotes (1 of 2), 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - ENDA history/footnotes (2 of 2), 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - ENDA Q and A, Undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Legislation/litigations, 1986-1994 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - The Washington Blade articles, 1970-1989 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - The Washington Blade articles, 1990-1994 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - The Washington Blade articles, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - The Washington Blade articles, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - The Washington Blade articles, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - ENDA Association (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Privacy - ENDA (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - State cases, 1983-1994 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Litigations, 1981-1992 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Memos, 1994-1998 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Legislation/litigation, 1990-1997 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - ENDA files, Undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - ENDA files, 1995-1997 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - ENDA files, 1991-1997 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - ENDA files, 1994-1999 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Religion, 1996-1997 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Education, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Human Rights Campaign Fund, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Section-by-section analysis, 1993-1994 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Employment discrimination cases (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Articles, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Discrimination claims - HCR LCCR, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Civil rights research, 1989-1994 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Ordinances (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous articles (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - City ordinances (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - S. 2238 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Memos - Law firms (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Cases (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Cases (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Responses to common arguments (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Statements/testimonies (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Preferential treatment (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Equal opportunity statements (universities, organizations) (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Summary of state experiences w/ employment discrimination laws (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - AIDS amendments, 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - American Psychological Association (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - H.R. 1863 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - People with AIDS/housing projects (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Disparate impact (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Title VI (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Title VII requests (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Military (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Religious organization exemptions (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - DOJ statement: Nondiscrimination in employment (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Metro Broadcasting vs. FCC (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Law Review article: Affirmative action and employment (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - ENDA: Responses to common arguments (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Memo: Federal statute on treatment of age discrimination (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - ENDA: Proposal on HRCF from Feldblum Group (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Law Review article: Homosexuality is Not a Civil Right (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Memo: HRCF on Boy Scouts (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Memo: Exemption for private membership clubs (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Memo: Why ENDA Belongs in Our Legal Code (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - ENDA and the status/conduct dilemma (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Feldblum: ENDA statement, 1996-12-04; tr-17382-17383 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    Includes two audiocassettes labeled "Gay Law Panel"
  - Judiciary Committee hearings: Intimidation and harassment based on sexual harassment, 1994-07-06 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Feldblum: ENDA statement - Senate Labor/HR, 1994-07-29 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Gay Rights Coalition of Georgetown University (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - ENDA: Table of Cases (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Family Research Council: Test on ENDA (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Broadus: Test on ENDA (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Senate Labor/HSS - ENDA Committee report (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1991 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Los Angeles County Bar Association Committee on Sexual Orientation Bias Report, 1994-06 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Anders: Ban Job Discrimination Against Gays and Lesbians (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Binder 1, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Binder 2, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Binder 3, 1992-1993 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Binder 4, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Binder 5, 1976-1997 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Binder 6, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Binder 7, 1991-1994 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Binder 8, 1991-1993 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Binder 9, 1994-1997 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Binder 10, 1995 -1997 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Binder 11, 1975-1992 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Binder 12, 1987-1997 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Binder 13, Part 1 of 2, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Binder 13, Part 2 of 2, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 2)